Preliminary Guide to the Liggett and Myers Tobacco Company Records, 1908-1980s RL.00813
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
The Liggett and Myers Tobacco Company records
1908-1980s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Liggett & Myers Tobacco Company
RL.00813
55.6 Linear Feet
18,206 Items
Access Restrictions
Access to parts of the collection are restricted.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The collection was received as a gift in 1999.
Historical Note
Liggett and Myers (now Liggett Group, Inc.) was founded in 1873 in Durham, N.C. The company became a major force in the tobacco industry offering such cigarettes as Fatima, a leading national brand in the early part of the 20th century.
Collection Overview
Collection consists primarily of advertisements for various Liggett and Myers tobacco products such as Chesterfield, Fatima, and Piedmont cigarettes, ca. 1910-1950s, as well as advertisements for competitors during the 1970s. Also included are scripts for radio and television commercials sponsored by Liggett and Myers during the 1950s.
The 2005 addition (2005-0058)(6 items, 0.6 lin. ft.) contains two use copy DVDs and two Betacam SP master copies of Liggett and Myers commercials found on film in the collection. These copies were made from the originals in the collection. Also included are radio scripts for Dragnet (1950) and Duke football games (1958-1959) that feature advertisements for Liggett and Myers products.
Advertising -- History; Broadcast advertising; Advertising -- Tobacco; Radio scripts; Tobacco industry -- North Carolina; Television scripts; Liggett & Myers Tobacco Company; Liggett & Myers Tobacco Company; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
- Accession #1999-366
  Scope and Contents note
  Note: Parts of this collection are restricted. Some materials are fragile and need further processing and conservation attention before researchers can use them. Please consult with a reference archivist for more information.
  - Advertisements: Fatima, 1908-1912 (Box 1)
  - Advertisements: Fatima, 1912-1919 (Box 2)
  - Advertisements: Fatima, 1913-1915 (Box 3)
  - Advertisements: Fatima, 1914-1915 (Box 4)
  - Advertisements: Fatima, 1915 (Box 5)
  - Advertisements: Fatima, 1917-1918 (Box 6)
  - Advertisements: Fatima, 1919 (Box 7)
  - Advertisements: Fatima, 1920 (Box 8)
  - Advertisements: Fatima, 1920 (Box 9)
  - Advertisements: Fatima, 1920 (Box 10)
  - Advertisements: Fatima, 1923-1928 (Box 11)
  - Advertisements: Fatima, 1930-1938, 1948-1955 (Box 12)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1924-1927 (RESTRICTED) (Box 13)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1926 (RESTRICTED) (Box 14)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1927-1929 (RESTRICTED) (Box 15)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1928 (RESTRICTED) (Box 16)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1929-1930 (RESTRICTED) (Box 17)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1929-1932 (RESTRICTED) (Box 18)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1930 (RESTRICTED) (Box 19)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1931 (RESTRICTED) (Box 20)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1931 (RESTRICTED) (Box 21)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1933 (RESTRICTED) (Box 22)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1933 (RESTRICTED) (Box 23)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1933 (RESTRICTED) (Box 24)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1933 (RESTRICTED) (Box 25)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1933 (RESTRICTED) (Box 26)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1934 (RESTRICTED) (Box 27)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1934 (RESTRICTED) (Box 28)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1934 (RESTRICTED) (Box 29)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1935 (RESTRICTED) (Box 30)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1935 (RESTRICTED) (Box 31)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1937-1938 (RESTRICTED) (Box 32)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1939 (RESTRICTED) (Box 33)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1939 (RESTRICTED) (Box 34)
  - Advertisements: Miscellaneous, 1910 (Box 35)
  - Advertisements: Miscellaneous, 1913-1915 (Box 36)
  - Advertisements: Miscellaneous, 1916 (Box 37)
  - Advertisements: Miscellaneous, 1916 (Box 38)
  - Advertisements: Miscellaneous, 1918-1919 (Box 39)
  - Advertisements: Miscellaneous, 1920 (Box 40)
  - Competitive Advertisements, 1921 (Box 41)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield and Fatima, 1926-1929 (Box 41)
  - Advertisements: Miscellaneous, 1931-1932 (Box 41)
  - Competitive Advertisements, ca. 1970s (Box 42)
    - Bel-Air, Benson and Hedges, Camel (Box 42)
  - Competitive Advertisements, ca. 1970s (Box 43)
    - Carlton, Doral, Fact, Gauloises, Iceberg 100s, Kent (Box 43)
  - Competitive Advertisements, ca. 1970s (Box 44)
    - Kool, Long Johns (Box 44)
  - Competitive Advertisements, ca. 1970s (Box 45)
    - Marlboro (Box 45)
  - Competitive Advertisements, ca. 1970s (Box 46)
    - Max, More, Newport, Now, Old Gold (Box 46)
  - Competitive Advertisements, ca. 1970s (Box 47)
    - Pall Mall, Parliament, Raleigh, Roal (Box 47)
  - Competitive Advertisements, ca. 1970s (Box 48)
    - Salem, Saratoga, Silva Thins, Suede, Tall (Box 48)
  - Competitive Advertisements, ca. 1970s (Box 49)
    - Tareyton, True, Vantage, Viceroy (Box 49)
  - Competitive Advertisements, ca. 1970s (Box 50)
    - Virginia Slims, Winston (Box 50)
  - Publicity Scrapbook #1, 1963-1974 (Box 51)
  - Publicity Scrapbook #2, 1975-1976 (Box 52)
  - Publicity Scrapbook #6, 1980-1981 (Box 53)
  - Publicity Scrapbook #7, 1982- 1983 (Box 54)
  - Publicity Scrapbook #8, 1984-1986 (Box 55)
  - Advertisements: Miscellaneous, 1920s (OVSZ) (Box 56)
  - Advertisements: Miscellaneous, 1931-1939 (OVSZ) (Box 57)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1926-1939, undated (OVSZ) (RESTRICTED) (Box 58)
  - Advertisements: Miscellaneous, 1924 (OVSZ) (Box 59)
  - Display Scrapbook, 1925 (Box 59)
  - Advertisements: Miscellaneous, 1950s-1970s (OVSZ) (Box 60)
  - Mechanicals/ Art Work (OVSZ) (Box 61)
  - Display Scrapbooks, 1933-1935 (OVSZ) (Box 62)
  - Display Scrapbooks, 1936, 1939 (OVSZ) (Box 63)
  - Display Scrapbooks, 1940-1942, 1949, 1954-1956 (OVSZ) (Box 64)
  - Radio and TV Scripts, 1949, 1956-1959 (Box 65)
    - Dragnet Fatima Radio, 1949 (Box 65)
    - Dragnet Fatima Radio, 1950 (Accession 2005-0058) (Box 65)
    - Dragnet Chesterfield TV, 1956 (Box 65)
    - Club Oasis (Cig.) TV Commercials, 1957-1958 (Box 65)
    - Eddie Fisher Show TV Commercials, 1957-1959 (Box 65)
    - Various Shows - Various Cigarettes, 1957-1958 (Box 65)
    - The Investigator (Box 65)
    - National Horse Show (Box 65)
    - Pied Piper (Box 65)
    - Ed Wynn (Box 65)
  - Radio and TV Scripts, 1957-1961 (Box 66)
    - Black Saddle TV Commercials, 1959 (Box 66)
    - D.A.'s Man TV Commercials, 1959 (Box 66)
    - Steve Canyon TV Commercials, 1958-1959 (Box 66)
    - Oasis Cig. Radio and TV Commercials, 1957-1960 (Box 66)
    - Duke Cig. Commercials, 1959-1961 (Box 66)
    - Liggett and Myers Broadcasts (Radio and TV), 1960-1961 (Box 66)
  - Index: contains Headline/ Slogan/ Description of ads from 1910-1923 (Box 66)
  - Conservation Problems (OVSZ) (RESTRICTED) (Box 67)
  - Advertisements: Miscellaneous, 1928-1974 (Box 96)
  - Mechanicals/Art work, ca. 1970s (Box 96)
- Accession # 2000-0126
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1931-1932 (RESTRICTED) (Box 68)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1932 (RESTRICTED) (Box 69)
  - Advertisements: Chesterfield, 1932 (RESTRICTED) (Box 70)
  - Advertisements: various, 1922-1934 (Box 71)
    - Includes ThreePak pipe tobacco (1922), Piedmont ( 1927-1928), Granger (1928), Spur (1934) (Box 71)
  - Advertisements: various, 1949-1965 (Box 72)
    - Includes Piedmont ( 1949), LandM ( 1957), Oasis ( 1957-1962), Devon ( 1964-1965) (Box 72)
  - Advertisements: various, 1970s-1980s (Box 73)
    - Includes LandM, Eve, Lark (Box 73)
  - Advertisements: various, 1970s-1980s (Box 74)
    - Includes St. Moritz, Dawn, Class A, Pyramid, Journey, Rainbow, Chesterfield (Box 74)
  - Advertisements: Non-tobacco, ca. 1970s (mostly liquor ads) (Box 75)
  - Advertisements (OVSZ): Point-of-purchase signs, ca. 1970s-1990s (Box 76)
  - Advertisements (OVSZ): Point-of-purchase signs, ca. 1970s-1990s (Box 77)
  - Advertisements (OVSZ): Point-of-purchase signs, ca. 1970s-1990s (Box 78)
  - Advertisements (OVSZ): various, 1974-1976 (Box 79)
    Includes Chesterfield ( 1974-1976), LandM ( 1974, 1976), Eagle ( 1976)
  - Advertisements (OVSZ): various, 1976-1978 (Box 80)
    Includes LandM, St. Moritz
  - Advertisements (OVSZ): various, 1978-1980 (Box 81)
    Includes LandM, Chesterfield
  - Advertisements (OVSZ): various, 1984 (Box 82)
    Includes Chesterfield, Decage, Omni, Lark, generics
  - Advertisements (OVSZ): various, 1984 (Box 83)
    Includes Eve Lights, multibrands (featuring several brands on a single ad)
  - Advertisements (OVSZ): various, 1984 (Box 84)
    Includes multibrands (FTCF files)
  - Advertisements (OVSZ): posters, 1970s-1980s (Box 85)
    Includes Lark, LandM, multibrands, and some liquor
  - Newspaper advertising for LandM Flavor Lights, 1976-1977 (for cities in OK, RI, NY, CT, NJ) (Box 86)
  - Newspaper advertising for LandM Flavor Lights, 1977 (for cities in CT, Mass) (Box 87)
  - International Spec Sheets describing competitor's product introduction worldwide, ca. 1970s (Box 88)
  - Radio/TV commercial scripts for Chesterfield, 1956-1960 (Box 88)
  - Radio commercial scripts for Duke football games, 1958 (Box 88)
  - Radio commercial scripts for Duke football games, 1958-1959 (Accession 2005-0058) (Box 88)
  - Broker Integration Manual (Liggett), ca. 1992 (includes industry overview and product information) (RESTRICTED) (Box 89)
  - Domestic Industry Overview, LandM Tobacco Co., ca. 1990s (RESTRICTED) (Box 89)
  - Liggett Group, Inc. Sales Plan, 1996 (RESTRICTED) (Box 89)
  - Client billing for ads of Oasis cigarettes by McCann Erickson agency, 1959 (Box 89)
  - Slide presentations, unidentified (Box 90)
  - FTC files related to LandM advertising, 1958-1958 (Box 90)
  - Film reels of television commercials, ca. 1963-1965 (RESTRICTED) (Box 91)
    Existence and Location of Copies note
    DVD use copies located in box 95
  - Comparative Results Book (for sales), 1923-1924 (Box 92)
  - Packaging samples, ca. 1970s (Box 93)
    - Includes LandM carton, Cork Dry Gin, Dukes of Durham cigarettes, and generic filter ultra lights cigarettes (Box 93)
- Accession, 2005 (2005-0058)
  The 2005 addition (2005-0058)(6 items, 0.6 lin. ft.) contains two use copy DVDs and two Betacam SP master copies of Liggett and Myers commercials found on film in the collection. These copies were made from the originals in the collection
  - Two Betacam SP tapes of Liggett and Myers commercials (RESTRICTED) (Box 94)
    Tapes are master copies of film reels of television commercials, ca. 1963-1965 located in box 91
    DVD use copies are located in box 95.
  - Two DVDs of Liggett and Myers commercials, ca. 1963-1965 (Box 95)
    These are master copies of film reels of television commercials, ca. 1963-1965 located in box 91.
- Oversize Materials
  Largely miscellaneous advertisements.
  - Advertisements, Miscellaneous (Box 96)
  - Advertisements, Miscellaneous (Oversize-folder 6)